[Mr. Liu,]
柳总
can we
要不咱们看看
meet up
什么时候有时间
and talk about it?
出来聊一聊呢
The commercial loan you've applied for
已经申请的商贷
can't be converted to a combined loan,
不能转成组合贷
but can only be switched to a housing loan.
只能转成公积金贷款
Right.
对
That depends on
那得看你
the balance in your
公积金账户的余额
account.
够不够了
Don't worry,
您放心我
I won't pressure you to buy.
不会逼着您买的
Right.
对
I can explain that.
您听一下
And it's up to you
要是觉得合适呢就接受
whether you accept or not.
不合适也无所谓的
It's definitely
那
a better deal
那肯定比商贷
than a commercial loan.
划算多了好吗
[You see,]
您看
[you and my boss]
您跟我们纪总呢
[are both from]
都是老乡
[the same hometown.]
从一个镇上出来的
Looking at it this way,
要是论起来的话
you're the person
您还是
he should respect.
我们纪总的长辈呢
Isn't that right?
是不是
[Okay.]
好 好 好
[Let's meet up in the next few days.]
那就这两天
Alright.
好的 好的
See you then.
那我们过两天见
Bye.
拜拜 拜拜
Xiaoning,
筱柠啊
the way you're
你现在打电话的
making calls now
这个方式吧
is just like
跟某人简直就是
certain someone.
如出一辙
[It doesn't feel like]
我感觉我一点
[I'm your mentor at all.]
都不像你师父
That Zhao...
那个赵
What's wrong?
怎么了
I am just
我这不是
drawing on your strengths.
采众家之长吗
Getting close to clients.
套近乎
As long as I can
只要能把客户
get them to meet.
约出来就行
That makes sense.
说得也对
Guys!
同志们
It's payday!
发工资了
You need to
财务催大家
hurry confirm
赶紧确认一下
your payment status.
收款状况
Leave your signatures,
签字
and collect your pay slips.
领工资条
That's great.
好事
Ms. Rao,
饶经理
I'll get it for you.
我去帮你领了
Hey,
不是
what are we? Why do I need you to do it?
咱俩什么关系你帮我领
You don't know
咱俩什么关系
what we are?
你不知道
What?
什么
We're creditor and debtor!
债主关系啊
Alright then.
行
Got it.
我明白
Some debts
有些债吧
can be postponed,
能拖
but some
有些债呀
can't.
不能拖
I'll get it right away.
我马上就去领
Yuhui,
小唐
why aren't you going?
你咋不去
I'll go after I finish this task.
我把这个忙完再去
[It's payday!]
发工资咯
[You need to sign to get your pay slip.]
要签字领工资条呢
[Could you help me take it?]
那你帮我领一下吧
[That wouldn't be appropriate.]
那多不合适呀
[You're authorized.]
纪总授权了
Done.
签好了
Sign here if you get it for others.
代领的在这儿签
Got it.
好
Here you go.
给
For Ji Yuheng.
纪昱恒的
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Why are you picking up
我师哥的工资条
Yuheng's pay slip?
为什么是你领啊
Ms. Rao just message me,
刚刚静姐给我发微信
asking me to get it for Mr. Ji.
让我帮一下忙
Why do you ask?
怎么了
No wonder.
难怪
I thought you weren't that close to him.
我说你跟他也没那么熟
Tang Yuhui.
唐羽卉
Come here.
来
I've transferred the money to you.
钱转你了赵经理
We're cleared.
以后人财两清
What's this?
什么意思
You just transferred it back.
钱又转回来了
Drinking with you in Xihai,
西海镇陪你喝酒
cooking for you during the New Year,
过年给你做饭
changing your tires,
轮胎我帮你换
bringing you breakfast,
早餐我帮你带
and making coffee for you...
咖啡我帮你泡
Should all these be free?
这些不需要利息的
You're raising the price, huh?
坐地起价啊
Yup!
对
Name a price.
说多少姐转你
How could you
什么意思呀
agree so easily?
这么痛快
You're not happy to get your money back?
还你钱你不高兴啊
When I loaned you the money,
借钱的时候
I felt being forced.
我是被迫出的
When it comes to repaying,
还钱的时候
I'm still forced to accept it.
我还是被迫接收的
Why am I always
凭什么我一直都是
the one being forced?
一个被迫选手
Allow me to refuse.
不同意
What do you want?
想怎么着
You'll have to repay me when I ask you to.
我让你还的时候你再还
Now you have the money back.
现在钱转给你了
You still owe me.
我还是你的债主
And I'd like to take advantage of it.
债主要行使债主的权利
Go to lunch with me.
陪我吃饭
No way.
吃不了
You know I'm someone
你知道我这个人
who has no boundaries.
做事没什么底线的
If this thing accidentally
万一这个事不小心
got out to everyone,
让大家伙知道了
then your dignity as Ms. Rao
那你饶经理的威严
would be undermined.
就扫地了
I am not afraid of that.
我饶静还怕那个
I'm not sure about that.
你怕不怕我不知道
But you know my talent for
但是我这添油加醋
exaggerating and
煽风点火的本领
stirring things up.
你是知道的
If you wanna turn this
你要是想把这件
simple matter
简单的事情
into a complicated one,
变复杂了
you could certainly try.
你可以试试嘛
Hey, Mr. Zhao,
不是我说赵经理
you've put in so great efforts
你上赶着请我吃饭
to buy me lunch, huh?
真是费尽了心思啊
Are you feeling right?
你有病吧你
I am unwell.
我是病了
Sick.
病了
So a patient wants you
那病人想让你
to have lunch together.
陪他吃个饭
Is that wrong?
有错吗
Is it contagious?
什么病传染吗
Nope.
不传染
OK, let's go then.
那吃吧
Here, take a bite.
尝一口啊
Be careful, it's hot.
慢点啊别烫着
How is it?
怎么样
Is it similar to what you make?
跟您做的一个味儿吗
Not quite the same.
不一样
It's even better
比我做得
than mine!
还好吃
Come on, mom.
妈你也太坏了吧
I was just thinking,
我还想呢
if I over-salted it
我说是不是我做咸了
or made it too bland,
或者是淡了
or maybe it wasn't
再不就是
cooked enough.
没煮熟
It's good!
好吃
Xiaoning,
筱柠啊
you've really
这两天
done a lot lately.
也真是辛苦你了
You've been coming here every day,
天天要跑医院
taking care of me.
给我忙前忙后的
And you even made dumplings today.
今天还包一顿饺子
You must be exhausted.
累坏了吧
Not at all.
不累
No worries.
我一点都不累
Seeing you get better every day
我看着你一天比一天好
makes me really happy.
我高兴还来不及呢
I'll eat later.
待会儿再吃
OK.
好
I'll just leave it here for now.
那就先放在这儿
Mom,
妈
Yuheng just got his paycheck.
我跟你说昱恒发工资了
I took a peek,
我偷偷看了一下
and there's a big sum of money!
有一大笔钱呢
We can go on a
咱们都可以来一个
luxurious road trip!
豪华自驾游了
Really?
真的
Mom, where do you want to go?
妈你想去哪儿
Let's go on a road trip!
咱们自驾游
I'll take you out to have some fun.
我带你出去玩
Sounds fantastic.
太好了
Yuheng
这昱恒
should be back soon, right?
也该回来了吧
[Unit 15,]
十五号床
[here are some forms for you.]
出来拿一些单子
He should
应该是
be back from
明天下午吧
a business trip tomorrow afternoon.
他就出差回来了
I'll come with him
到时候
to pick you up.
我跟他一起来接你出院
Good.
好
Xiaoning,
筱柠啊
I can eat by myself.
我自己吃可以的
You should take a break.
你歇一歇
You've been busy all day.
忙一天了
Just take a nap.
眯一会儿也好
I'm good, really.
我真不累
You want to eat by yourself.
你自己吃呢
That's fine.
倒是也行
I'll just go wash the dishes,
我正好去洗个碗
and I'll be back soon.
很快就回来
Take care.
吃的时候千万别烫着
Xiaoning,
筱柠
these dumplings
这个饺子
are yummy.
真的很好吃
Thanks.
谢谢
Hello?
喂
How's the deal going?
合同签得怎么样
Is everything going well?
一切都顺利吗
The contract has been confirmed
合同之前跟对方的
with their accounting and legal teams.
财务和法务已经确认过
So it went well.
签约的流程就很顺利
Good.
好
[Passengers of flight 163]
乘坐南北航空
[of Nanbei Airlines,]
一六三次航班的旅客
[are now boarding.]
请注意登机
You
你
have arrived at the airport?
到机场了
Yeah.
对
After the meeting,
忙完之后
I bought the ticket right away.
我直接买的机票
I'll be in Xingcheng tonight.
今天晚上可以到星城
Mom was just talking about you.
妈刚才还念叨你呢
She misses you.
说她想你了
If she knew you're coming back tonight,
她要知道你今晚就回来
she would be so happy.
肯定特别开心
OK.
那好
Let's meet tonight.
咱晚上到了见
Take care.
一路平安
Let's go check it out!
走 过去看看
Excuse me.
不好意思
Mom!
妈
Please step outside.
家属请到外边来
I know.
我知道
Let me see her.
我看她一眼
Don't interfere with our rescue efforts.
不要影响我们抢救病人
Excuse me.
不好意思 不好意思
My mom must be scared all by herself.
我妈一定会害怕的
Mom!
妈
Please stay outside.
家属请在外面
Mom, are you alright?
妈你怎么了
[Please.]
不要影响
- Calm down! - Mom!
我们抢救病人 妈
Yuheng will be back soon!
妈昱恒马上就回来
Allow me in!
你让我进去
Mom!
妈
I'm really sorry.
对不起
We did our best.
我们尽力了
Doctor!
大夫
Please try to save her!
麻烦你再救一下吧
Please stay calm, OK?
请您冷静 好不好
Her son will be back soon.
她儿子马上就回来
Please don't give up on her!
你 你别放弃
Doctor!
大夫
Let go of me!
你干吗放开我
- Doctor! - Please calm down.
大夫 冷静 冷静
I can't!
我冷静不了
How can I calm down?
我怎么冷静
Mom!
妈
Yuheng will be back soon.
昱恒马上就回来了
just wait for him, please!
你再等等他好不好
How can I explain
你这样让我
this to him?
怎么跟他交代呀
Xiaoning.
筱柠
Mom.
妈
It's OK.
没事啊
I'm here.
妈妈在呢
Mom.
妈
How could this happen?
怎么会那么突然啊
She was fine in the morning.
今天白天还好好地
Her spirits were really high.
精神状态可好了
She even said
我婆婆还说
that the dumplings I made were yummy.
我包的饺子好吃
She was chatting and laughing with me.
她还跟我有说有笑地
She kept asking me
她一直在问我说
when Yuheng would be back.
说昱恒什么时候回来
Mom,
妈
days ago, she's fine
我们前两天
when we returned to our hometown.
回老家的时候还好好地
It's all my fault.
都怪我
I just stepped out
我刚才出去
to wash dishes,
洗个碗的工夫
then this happened.
就这样了
If I hadn't gone out,
我要是不出去洗碗的话
she would have been fine.
她就不会这样了
No,
没有
it has nothing to do with you.
没有跟你没关系
It's OK.
好了
She
不是
kept asking me earlier
她刚刚一直在问我
when Yuheng would be back.
昱恒什么时候回来
Mom, do you think
妈你说
that she actually
我婆婆是不是
sensed something?
感知到了什么
She wanna see her son one last time.
她就想见儿子最后一面
But she didn't even get that chance.
这最后一面也没见成
When Yuheng comes back,
等昱恒回来了
I don't know how to explain it to him.
我也没法跟他交代
What can I tell him?
我怎么跟他说呀
It's OK.
好了 好了 好了
It's alright.
没事啊
Mom.
妈
Yuheng.
小纪
I'm sorry.
对不起
It's OK.
没事
I'm back.
我回来了
I'm sorry.
对不起
Here.
来
Mom,
妈
aunt is here to see you.
表姨她来看你了
Aunt,
表姨
my mom often thinks about you.
我妈她常常挂念你
She must be happy
您能来
to see you here.
她肯定很高兴
Your mom has
你妈这辈子
had a tough life.
太不容易了
She finally enjoyed a few days...
好不容易享了几天的福
Aunt.
来表姨
Please take care of yourself.
您也多注意身体
Please, this way.
来 这边
- Yuheng. - Mom, dad.
小纪 爸妈
It's
这
almost done
差不多
in here.
都完事了
Is there anything else
你看还有
that we can help you with?
需要我们做的地方
Nothing.
没什么了
Thank you so much.
你们也辛苦了
We're family. No need for thanks.
这一家人不说两家话
If you need us,
需要我们
just let us know.
做什么呢尽管说一声
You must be tired after such a long day.
这一天下来你也够累的
You should get some rest.
抽空好好休息休息
Dad, mom,
爸 妈
you should also get some rest.
你们也去休息休息吧
Xiaoning,
筱柠
my condolences.
节哀
Later, Qi Yu and I
一会我和齐郁
will buy you food.
一起去买点吃的
I know you don't have
我知道这个时候
much of an appetite,
你胃口不好
but you need to take care of yourself.
但是身子也不能垮了呀
If something happens to you,
你身子要是垮了
Ji Yuheng will be devastated.
纪昱恒怎么办
I know.
我知道
This is a token from me
这一份是我作为师父
as your mentor.
给你的
Here.
来
Take it.
拿着
My condolences.
节哀
Jing,
静姐
I...
我
My relationship with Mr. Ji...
我 我跟纪总的关系
No worries.
行了
Don't say it.
别说了
I already know.
我都知道了
I should have figured it out sooner.
我其实早该知道
Nothing can be hidden from you.
什么都瞒不过静姐
I have a feeling that
我本来呢
something has happened between you.
猜到你们有点什么
But I didn't expect
但是我没有想到
you two to go this far.
已经走到这一步了
Actually, we haven't...
其实也没有
Last time I went to the hospital
上次我去医院
to visit Mr. Ji's mom,
看望纪总妈妈的时候
I already knew.
就已经知道了
And I saw that you and your mother-in-law
而且我看你跟你婆婆
were quite close.
挺亲近的
Now that she's gone,
所以她走了
you must be very sad.
你一定很难过吧
Keep it up.
好了
Take care of yourself.
好好的啊
I'm leaving now.
我走了
They left?
人呢
Yes.
走了
All of them?
都走了
C'mon, what do you wanna say?
你有话就说
I planned to invite you
本来想约你
for afternoon tea.
去喝下午茶的
But facing such an incident,
老纪家出这么大的事
it wouldn't be appropriate for us
我俩再出去潇洒
to go out and have fun.
太不合时宜了
Why do you say that?
有什么不合时宜的
The dead have gone.
死了的人死了
Those living must continue to live, right?
活着的人总得活吧
I realized it
这个道理呢
at the moment
我在很久以前
I lost my parents
没有爸妈的那一刻
so long ago.
就明白了
You were so young
你那么小
to handle a funeral.
操办父母的后事
That must be tough.
挺不容易的
It's been too long.
时间太久了
I can't remember.
不记得了
But you...
倒是你啊
Why do you
赵经理
suddenly seem so refined?
怎么突然小资起来
Having afternoon tea?
还喝下午茶
I...
我
pursue...
追求
a fulfilling life.
生活
The ambiance matters, you know.
情调不行啊
Cool.
行啊
Let's go for it!
走呗
OK.
好
I'll just grab my bag.
我取包
I'll drive.
我开车
I never thought you would
没想到赵经理
actually buy me afternoon tea.
真的请喝下午茶呀
And even
还来这么
at such a charming place.
有氛围感的地方
But I'm concerned
可是我担心
that after I take a sip,
我这一口茶下去
you might ask me to split the bill.
你不会找我平摊钱吧
Am I really that
我是这么
stingy to you?
小气巴拉的人吗
No,
你不是
you're just frugal.
你是抠
Alright then.
行
Today, your little jab
今天你对我这个
at my character
不准确地评价
ends here.
也就到此为止了
Let me show you
我让你看看
what true generosity looks like.
什么叫大方啊
Waiter!
服务员
I was just wondering
我就说
why you would treat me
为什么平白无故
to afternoon tea out of the blue.
请我喝下午茶
You helped a friend buy a bag.
帮朋友买包
You want me to check it out for you?
让我给你长长眼
Alright then.
行
You know,
我跟你说呀
if you're worried about
你要一开始
getting a fake one,
怕买到假包
you should have come to me.
你就应该找我
A purchasing agent wasn't necessary.
不应该找代购
I bought it from the store.
这是专柜里抱出来的
Give it a try?
试试
There's really no such thing as
天底下真是没有
a free lunch in this world.
免费的午餐啊
I have to help you try it on?
还得帮你试背
Well, since I'm here,
行来都来了
I might as well help you out.
帮你背一下啊
Let's see how it looks.
看看
Good?
好看吗
Totally.
好看
Really?
是吗
It suits you perfectly.
非常适合你
Do you like it?
喜欢吗
What do you mean by that?
几个意思啊
Just as I said.
就这个意思
This bag
这个包
is a gift for you.
送给你的
I was planning to wait for a
我本来想找个
special occasion to give it to you.
合适的日子再送
But I thought
但我估计
you might be feeling down today,
你今天心情不好
so I decided to give it to you now.
所以我就提前送给你了
How did you know
你哪儿看出来
I was feeling down?
我心情不好
Just a little while ago.
就刚才那一会儿啊
You looked at Mr. Ji three times,
你一共看了老纪三次
and your eyes turned tearful twice.
眼睛红了两回
You even turned away to avoid being seen.
还故意转过头怕人看见
Honestly, I noticed something was off
其实在西海镇的时候
about you back in Xihai Town.
我就发现你状态不对了
Rao Jing,
饶静
we've known each other for so long.
咱俩都这么熟了
You don't need to
你在我面前
put on a front with me.
没必要一直端着吧
I won't
我就
wrap it up for you.
不帮你包了
I see there's a receipt.
我看小票也有
You could sell it for a good price
拿到这个二手市场
in a second-hand market
应该能卖不少钱
What do you mean?
什么意思啊
I'm not taking it.
这包我不要
Rao Jing!
饶静
Why are you leaving?
你走什么呀
If you don't like this one,
你要是不喜欢这款
no problem.
那也行
I'm going all out here.
我豁出去了
You can choose one you like.
你挑个你喜欢的
Zhao Fanggang!
赵方刚
Who am I to you?
我跟你什么关系
Why spend so much on me?
你至于这么大放血吗
Even if you won the lottery today,
就算你今天中彩票了
you shouldn't be spending
你钱也不应该花在
any part of it on me.
我身上啊
Also,
还有
why do you care so much about me?
你这么关心我干什么
My eyes turned red.
我眼睛红了几次
I was looking at Mr. Ji.
我看了纪总几眼
My condition was bad.
我状态对不对
What does this have to do with you?
跟你有什么关系啊
Are you the type who,
你是不是平时在外边
as long as you have a romantic interest,
只要有个暧昧对象
you're this
你对她们就
attentive and caring?
都这么细心暖男
How warm-hearted you are!
中央空调呢
Rao Jing,
饶静
I'm confused.
你把我说糊涂了
Cut to the chase.
我不明白
What do you wanna say?
你到底什么意思啊
I mean,
我的意思是
I've noticed
我发现
you're being serious with me.
你要跟我玩真的
That's right.
对
So what?
怎么了
Listen.
没怎么
If it's just for fun
如果只是玩玩呢
I'm game for anything,
怎么极限拉扯都可以
no matter how extreme.
我奉陪到底
We're all adults here.
大家都成年人了
Single.
单身
Bored.
无聊
Just looking for fun.
解闷
But if you
但是如果
are serious about this
你跟我玩真的
and want a stable relationship...
想进入一段稳定的感情
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm not looking for that.
我没有这个打算
Zhao Fanggang,
赵方刚
you're taking this way too seriously
你现在太认真了
that it's hard for me to keep up.
你认真到我都玩不起了
So,
所以
you're eager to return the money,
你着急还我钱
just to draw a line with me.
就是想跟我划清界限
No need to draw a line for flirting.
暧昧的那个线不用划
I'm drawing a line for seriousness.
我划的是认真的那个线
And right now, you've crossed it.
而你现在呢踩线了
It's just not fun anymore.
就没劲了
So in your eyes,
原来在你眼里
I'm no different
我跟那些
from those boys that
逗闷子的小男孩
you fool around with.
没什么区别
I'll go boil some water
我去烧点水
for you to soak your feet.
给你泡泡脚吧
Alright?
好吧
I'll get your flip-flops.
我去给你拿鞋
Darling.
老涂
Sit here.
你坐这儿
I want to talk to you for a bit.
我想跟你说会儿话
In the future,
以后
if you want to go out and dance,
你想跳广场舞
just go ahead.
就去跳广场舞
I don't mind
想跟张桂英跳
if your dance partner
就跟张桂英跳
is Lucy or Lily,
想跟李桂英跳
whoever.
就跟李桂英跳
As long as it makes you happy.
你高兴就行
I've come to understand.
我想明白了
We're at an age where
咱们都这个年纪了
we're already retired.
也退休了
The kids have their own lives now.
孩子们也有自己的生活
We should
咱俩
do things that
就去做一些
make us happy, right?
让自己高兴的事情好吗
If we have fun things to do
要是每天
every day, then...
都有开心的事情
It's OK.
不难过了啊
No worries.
不难过了
From now on,
以后
I always take you
我再跳舞的时候
with me when I
我每一回
go out to dance.
我都带上你
Alright?
好吧
I'll teach you if you don't know how.
你不会我教给你
If you don't like it,
你要不喜欢
we can do something
咱就去做点
you enjoy,
你喜欢干的事
like shopping
咱们可以去 去
together,
我陪你逛街
finding someone to play cards with,
咱们找人打牌
or exploring
咱们去出去玩
the mountains and rivers.
游山玩水去
Good?
好吧
In the past,
以前哪
I always thought
我总觉得
that life was long ahead of us.
这日子还长着呢
But after this,
可是经历这一遭啊
I suddenly realized
我才突然意识到
that life is unpredictable.
世事无常啊
So let's cherish every moment.
且过且珍惜吧
I just can't accept it.
我就是受不了
How could one person
你说好好的一个人
just vanish like that?
怎么说没就没了呢
Today, when I saw Yuheng's lonely image,
我今天看着小纪的背影
I couldn't help but wonder,
我就在想
what if it were us?
要是轮到咱俩
Xiaoning...
筱柠
What would happen to her?
筱柠怎么办
Here.
给
No matter what,
那在怎么
it's impossible
也不可能
to be there for the child forever.
陪孩子一辈子
Right?
对吧
But we can
但是咱们可以
start living
从今天开始
a healthy life
咱们
from today.
健康地生活
We can maintain a positive mood.
有一个好的心情
That way,
这样
we can stay
咱们是不是
with our daughter
就可以陪闺女
longer.
久一些了
Right?
对不
I'd like to soak my feet.
那我要泡脚
OK.
泡脚
Let me take off your shoes.
我给你脱鞋
One sec.
等着啊
You've been worn out these days.
这些天你累坏了
I can see the red veins
我看你眼睛里
in your eyes.
都有红血丝了
You should get some rest.
你去休息一下好不好
I'm fine.
没关系的
Now it's just the two of us.
现在就我们两个人
If you have anything on your mind,
你有什么心里话
you can share with me.
就跟我说说
If you're
你要是
sad,
心里难受
you can hold me and let it out.
你抱着我哭一场
Would that help?
会不会好一些
It's alright.
没关系
I'm OK.
我没事的
Don't worry about me.
放心吧
I'm just a little tired.
就是真的有点累了
I understand.
知道
Get some rest.
你先休息会儿
I'll go cook.
我去做饭
Let me handle it.
还是我去吧
Turn on the lights,
把灯打开
it'll make you feel better.
心里敞亮点
I know you're sad,
我知道你心里不舒服
and you don't have much of an appetite.
也没什么胃口
You should eat a little.
但还是吃点吧
Otherwise, mom would worry about you.
不然妈知道了会心疼的
OK.
好
How is it?
怎么样
Good?
好吃吗
Mom said that
妈说了
it tastes
我做的
as good as
跟她做的味道
what she made.
一样好吃呢
I thought I'd never have
我以为我再也吃不到
this flavor again.
这个味道了
My mom has gone.
我妈真的走了
I don't have a mom anymore.
我没妈了
While sorting through mom's belongings,
刚刚收拾妈遗物的时候
I found this album.
发现了这个相册
Take a look.
看看
In the hospital,
住院的时候呢
she always wrote
她就总是在这个相册上
and drew in it
写写画画的
Turns out, it was all for you.
原来都是写给你的
You've never seen these, have you?
这些你也都没见过吧
This was from when I was two.
两岁那天
I had a birthday party.
我过生日
When I was in kindergarten,
幼儿园的时候
I even took gymnastics classes.
还上过体操课呢
In the future, when we have these photos,
以后等有了这些照片
we can put them in here.
我们再把它们放上去
Take a look further.
你看看后面
You have more.
后面还有
Mom left you some words.
妈妈给你写的话
[Yuheng,]
小恒
[I'm in the hospital again.]
妈妈又住院了
[This time,]
这次
[I don't know how long I can be with you.]
不知道还能陪你多久
[Because of my condition,]
为了我的病
[you gave up your dream job]
你放弃理想中的工作
[but to work in sales.]
到业务部门
[You've been working so hard.]
辛苦奔波
[I know it clearly.]
妈妈看在眼里
[I feel so guilty.]
很内疚
[But more than that,]
但更多的
[I feel heartbroken.]
是心疼
[One day I'm no longer here,]
如果有一天我走了
[I hope you can find peace,]
希望你能放松下来
[and do things you love.]
做一些喜欢的事
[Live happily]
和筱柠一起
[with Xiaoning.]
好好生活
[Our family's journey,]
咱们一家人的缘分
[though brief,]
虽然不长
[has been meaningful all along.]
但人生这一路上
[With your dad,]
有你爸爸
[you,]
你
[and Xiaoning by my side,]
和筱柠陪着
[I feel truly content.]
妈妈很知足
[Thank you, Yuheng.]
谢谢你小恒
[Your dad and I]
我和你爸爸
[will always]
会一直
[watch over you.]
守护你们的
Mom can rest easy knowing
妈妈应该可以放心
that the two of us
我们两个
will take good care of ourselves.
会好好照顾好自己的
We definitely will.
一定会的
Morning.
起了
You've already made breakfast?
你都做好早餐啦
You...
你
Are you
今天打算
gonna work today?
去上班
I'm planning to take a break.
我准备休息一下
I need some time to heal.
给自己一个调整的时间
I'll go ask for leave later.
一会儿去行里请个假
I'll be here for you.
我陪你一起调整
No need for that.
不用
Just focus on work.
你该上班上班
Don't worry about me.
放心吧
I won't do anything
我不会做任何
that would make you worry.
让你担心的事情
[He has to]
这段日子
[find his way]
终究是得
[out of this all by himself.]
让他自己走出来
OK.
好
[You look good.]
状态不错
About this filling,
这个馅啊
the key is the oil.
它的关键就是这个料油
Mom, you look great in photos.
妈好上相啊
Listen to me.
听我说啊
First,
就是
you need to use hot oil to activate it.
先用热油激一下
But,
但是
you must be
关键啊
careful not to use
一个是油的量
too much oil.
不能太多
Or
多了呢
it'll be greasy.
就腻了
One more thing.
还有一个呢就是
It must be cooked
一定要小火
on low heat
不然的话那个火一大
to avoid making it burn.
它下去就煳了
Then, you'll get a good flavor.
就没有香味了
This really is a meticulous job.
这还真是个细致活呢
Looks okay.
看差不多
Does it smell good?
闻着香味了没
Alright.
好的
Now pour out
然后把料油
the oil.
空出来
Mom, don't worry. I'll get it right.
妈你放心我肯定好好学
I'll handle the cooking.
以后呢就我来做
I won't let you wear yourself out.
不让你挨累
Never mind.
学不会也没关系
I can do it
你们要想吃
for you at any time,
妈就给你们做
and as much as you want.
想吃多少妈做多少